[{"id": "5ab99b6921a8909e5c332d2b", "question": "What year saw the release of the film \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit\"?", "answer": "1988", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c5", "question": "In 1643 Evangalista Torichelli invented the first what?", "answer": "Barometer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388cb", "question": "Which Oscar Wilde character stayed young as his picture aged?", "answer": "Dorian Gray", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff25b1c31a458464a93c476", "question": "In what year were the first Air Jordan sneakers released?", "answer": "1984", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339376", "question": "In the movie \"Batman\", who claims to weigh 108 lbs?", "answer": "Vickie Vale", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a24", "question": "What European capital city was the setting for the musical \"Cabaret\"?", "answer": "Berlin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c37cc815febcc896f9274", "question": "What is the third sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Gemini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9fb", "question": "Who were the two founders of the company \"Hewlett-Packard\"?", "answer": "Bill Hewlett and Dave Packard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339546", "question": "What TV show starred Suzanne Somers as Carol Foster/Lambert?", "answer": "Step by Step", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d56", "question": "Each of the Gorillaz' first two albums has a song named in honor of what actor?", "answer": "Clint Eastwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a955961d1b4d384d5d678", "question": "Which fruit is affected by a grey type of fungus known commonly as Noble Rot?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe1ef0d145fb2946670738b", "question": "\"The Champagne Of Bottled Beer\" has been which company's ad slogan?", "answer": "Miller Beer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ac", "question": "What A-Team cast member was once a bodyguard for Muhammad Ali and Leon Spinks?", "answer": "Mr. T", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339163", "question": "Who created the cartoon TV show \"Futurama\"?", "answer": "Matt Groening", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339107", "question": "In the painting \"American Gothic\", who are the models said to have been modelled after?", "answer": "The painter's sister and his dentist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd66a28a5bfecdd737e0880", "question": "Where is the last remaining Blockbuster store?", "answer": "Bend, Oregon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a647", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Colorado?", "answer": "Denver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ecd", "question": "Who fights crime alongside a German shepherd named Ace?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c440", "question": "What ape has a name derived from Malay for \"man of the forest\"?", "answer": "Orangutan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c576", "question": "Which planet in our solar system is known as the Earth's twin?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339299", "question": "What is the main difference between the character Starbuck in the 70's version of \"Battlestar Galact", "answer": "Starbuck is a female in the reboot and a male in the 70's version", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e73206d333868d34d73b", "question": "What was the \"Seven Foot Pilum\" in the Roman arsenal of weapons?", "answer": "A javelin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe37a5f0ada16518afdc058", "question": "What two countries declared war on Germany after it invaded Poland?", "answer": "Great Britain and France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d8e", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Christmas with the Kranks\" based on?", "answer": "Skipping Christmas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76e15eec85e375820b2d9", "question": "Which country did Barbados gain its independence from?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a996", "question": "In what country would you find the active volcano \"Lassen Peak\"?", "answer": "The United States", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e8", "question": "What country did writer Arthur C. Clarke die in?", "answer": "Sri Lanka", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3cc", "question": "What is the northernmost Scandinavian country?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a899bd260d398dc9cf7a6a1", "question": "What is the capital of Madagascar?", "answer": "Antananarivo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a162a64f01ec323f8491723", "question": "What carries sensations from the tongue to the brain?", "answer": "Lingual nerve", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af49", "question": "Where was Albert Einstein born?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b6", "question": "Which English city was actor Stephen Fry born in?", "answer": "London", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a119", "question": "Which classic Hollywood western is based on the film \"Seven Samurai\"?", "answer": "The Magnificent Seven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0c6", "question": "What was the Tuxedo named after?", "answer": "Tuxedo Park, New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c3e97e4ebfabb9c85d8a967", "question": "What is the stage name of Harry Webb?", "answer": "Cliff Richard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a1", "question": "Who was the voice of Darth Vader in the original Star Wars movie?", "answer": "James Earl Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4eacd06d333868d34d75d", "question": "Who was the first democratically elected president of Russia?", "answer": "Boris Yeltsin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339229", "question": "Who is pictured with her eyes wide open on posters for Kubrick's \"Eyes Wide Shut\" movie?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600243224be4723ccac22191", "question": "Charles Marlow is the narrator of which Joseph Conrad novella?", "answer": "\"Heart of Darkness\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "596dfee79616e6c6d4eba4fd", "question": "The Artful Dodger is a character from which novel? ", "answer": "Oliver Twist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b70", "question": "What city did the S.S. Minnow leave from on its three-hour tour on the original TV series \"Gilligan's Island\"?", "answer": "Honolulu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062c0dc9d816e292245c28", "question": "What art movement was Yoko Ono associated with during the 1960s?", "answer": "Yoko Ono helped to define the\u00a0Fluxus\u00a0movement in 1960s  New York, which was part Dada, part Bauhaus and part Zen.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b358dba5db0d66a186cb563", "question": "If a chemical is \"anhydrous\", what does it not contain?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f1671af7c52aae91cc07b5", "question": "What was the codename of the Allied invasion of French North Africa in 1942?", "answer": "Operation Torch", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc38", "question": "What was the motto of the 1972 Munich Olympic games?", "answer": "The Happy Games", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e9b6fe83fe1f2a824beb", "question": "Queen Mary Tudor of England is better known to history by what name?", "answer": "Bloody Mary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4da", "question": "Which is larger, a baseball or a softball?", "answer": "A softball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7abaff6490a8cc1a6e5293", "question": "In Roman numerals, what number does \"D\" represent?", "answer": "500", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ba", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Romeo and Julie\", what is Romeo's surname?", "answer": "Montague", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e3", "question": "What was W. C. Fields' birth name?", "answer": "William Claude Dukenfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c0", "question": "What \"Pink Panther\" director produced the TV show \"Peter Gunn\"?", "answer": "Blake Edwards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c3721815febcc896f926d", "question": "What is a group of mallards in flight called?", "answer": "A Sord", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4b3ab06d333868d34d6db", "question": "Easter was named from what Anglo-Saxon goddess?", "answer": "Eostre", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaed", "question": "Dodoma is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Tanzania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a347", "question": "What decade did the TV special \"It's the Great Pumpkin, Charlie Brown\" come out in?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c8749076251badbead6", "question": "What was the first country to put a woman in space?", "answer": "The Soviet Union -- In 1963, cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova\u00a0orbited the Earth 48 times in a space capsule named Vostok 6.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b466", "question": "What year did General Sherman order Atlanta be burned?", "answer": "1864", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd6", "question": "What TV show did \"Diagnosis Murder\" spin off from?", "answer": "Jake and the Fatman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab5a", "question": "What sea does the river Elbe flow into?", "answer": "North Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5921fce4a4edfd43a087adc4", "question": "What number is represented by \"X\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "10", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b07", "question": "What is the name of the Wally World mascot in \"National Lampoon's Vacation\"?", "answer": "Marty Moose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bcd", "question": "Boy George's music is often classified as what unique genre?", "answer": "Blue-eyed soul", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca9e", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Sodium?", "answer": "Na", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133944e", "question": "How many times did Peter Sellers play Inspector Clouseau?", "answer": "Six", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396eb", "question": "On the Academy Awards statue, what is Oscar standing on?", "answer": "A reel of film", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049d91cf93664eb10486ae", "question": "The plane carrying what country\u2019s national rugby team crashed on Friday, October 13, 1972?", "answer": "Uruguay\u2019s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe768aaeec85e375820b2a4", "question": "What country once had a banknote that featured a woman riding a shark?", "answer": "Cook Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c2", "question": "Heineken beer originated in which country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c140", "question": "Which brand name gets its name from the Finnish for \"Wild Grass\"?", "answer": "Timotei", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e1fefe83fe1f2a824b9b", "question": "What was Hitler\u2019s primary justification for invading Russia?", "answer": "Germany needed more space for its population.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e22", "question": "What city's orchestra did Eugene Ormandy conduct for forty-four years?", "answer": "Philadelphia's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad9df61e748bb36357acde8", "question": "The City of Hot Coffee is in what US state?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e6b3bdfb6c85e9e634ff43", "question": "In architecture, what is the structure that forms the arms of a cross-shaped church named?", "answer": "Transept", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb08b7e83c707845b2105", "question": "What\u2019s the botanical term for the stem of a fruit or vegetable?", "answer": "Peduncle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf44", "question": "How many bits was the Intel 4004 chip?", "answer": "4 bits", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbca", "question": "Who was the first head coach to win three Super Bowls?", "answer": "Chuck Noll", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac04", "question": "Yaren is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Nauru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd9701f23c87fd04dd15e46", "question": "Which President banned Christmas trees from the White House?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa5265c73aa70ea0b70b1a", "question": "The Po River is the longest river in which country?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f2f", "question": "Which band member of Milli Vanilli died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Rob Pilatus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f1648b6f9b80650dbe7f927", "question": "In what movie was the song \"Speechless\"?", "answer": "Aladdin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa7", "question": "Frank Zappa's 1979 album \"Sheik Yerboutti\" was a salute to what band's 1976 hit?", "answer": "KC and the Sunshine Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338876", "question": "Who does Alice follow down the hole?", "answer": " The White Rabbit", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a9a", "question": "In the children?s nursery rhyme, what comes next after ?Mary, Mary quite contrary??", "answer": "How does your garden grow?", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0afcae662d71a53650fc3", "question": "Who is Fridwulfa the mother of?", "answer": "Rubeus Hagrid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b749", "question": "What 1996 Olympic event had two US squads playing each other for the gold medal?", "answer": "Beach volleyball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a50", "question": "In the tale \"Jack and the Beanstalk\", what did Jack trade for the magic beans?", "answer": "A cow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b6", "question": "Who did Abraham Lincoln face in a series of debates in 1858?", "answer": "Stephen Douglas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b7a", "question": "What political event does not bother Lynyrd Skynyrd in their song \"Sweet Home Alabama\"?", "answer": "Watergate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339889", "question": "What 1987 Michael Caine film has a zero rating on the website Rotten Tomatoes?", "answer": "Jaws 4 - The Revenge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc0", "question": "Whose profile is displayed on the Purple Heart medal?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339896", "question": "Who won an Oscar for this role in the movie \"The Philadelphia Story\"?", "answer": "James Stewart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b973", "question": "Which Scotland Yard detective lead the hunt for Ronnie Biggs in the sixties?", "answer": "Jack Slipper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3e8da38e4e5d4832e630c", "question": "What was the name of Mussolini's Yacht in World War II?", "answer": "Aurora", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d93", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Dennis Coles?", "answer": "Ghostface Killah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51301ff04d658268c92d5", "question": "Where was Adolf Hitler born?", "answer": "Hitler was born in Braunau am Inn, a town in Austria-Hungary (present-day Austria)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395fd", "question": "\"Pizza the Hut\" was the villain in what sci-fi spoof?", "answer": "Spaceballs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa50", "question": "What is the capital of Saint Vincent and the Grenadines?", "answer": "Kingstown", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f1", "question": "What was compiled and published for the first time, in New York, in 1936?", "answer": "Pop music chart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3c6344f0f6af5b066630", "question": "Nuclear membrane, cytoplasm, and nucleus are parts of a what?", "answer": "Cell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b01", "question": "What is the name of the crab who looks after Ariel in Disney's \"The Little Mermaid\"?", "answer": "Sebastian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59636abd967692ea8518999f", "question": "Which two cross-border neighbouring cities jointly celebrate July 1 and July 4 holidays with the International Freedom Festival?", "answer": "Windsor and Detroit", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60173fab44491cbd7c5a17b4", "question": "What general commanded the American Expeditionary Forces on the Western Front during World War I?", "answer": "John Joseph \"Black Jack\" Pershing GCB", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b28", "question": "What jazz singer was the U2 song Angel of Harlem about?", "answer": "Billie Holiday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133997b", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Lenny's ex-wife?", "answer": "Emma", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339269", "question": "Who played Mad Max Rockatansky?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c6e40775fa611bce67d4", "question": "A legislature that has legislators in two separate assemblies, chambers, or houses is called what?", "answer": "Bicameral", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339883", "question": "In Harry Potter, who is it that reveals to Harry that he is a wizard?", "answer": "Hagrid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea8025ff048f679a45ac18", "question": "What period did the Tyrannosaurus Rex live during?", "answer": "Cretaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd1e", "question": "What computer language uses as its logo a blue mug with red steam rising from it?", "answer": "Java", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecd4c9ec223966ae8f88cd", "question": "What was the first Disney animated film based on the life of a real person?", "answer": "\"Pocahontas\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c62f", "question": "Long-period comets are believed to come from where?", "answer": "The Oort Cloud", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015eac4fe83fe1f2a824bf4", "question": "What does the color white represent in the American flag?", "answer": "White symbolizes purity and innocence.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bded", "question": "What is the 3 letter code for O'Hare International Airport?", "answer": "ORD", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601217f363c99d48cd169aed", "question": "The penny-farthing was a popular type of what?", "answer": "Bicycle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c284", "question": "How would you write 99 in Roman numerals?", "answer": "XCIX", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339690", "question": "What is the name of King Arthur's sidekick in the 1975 movie \"Monty Python and the Holy Grail\"?", "answer": "Patsy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c299", "question": "What is the hardest substance in the human body?", "answer": "Enamel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "593c4b5db8198b9a2b077963", "question": "The film \"Casablanca\" takes place during which war?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a39", "question": "What former \"Little House on the Prairie\" star served two consecutive terms as president of the Screen Actors Guild?", "answer": "Melissa Gilbert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c12b877e98cb97778974", "question": "Where is Graceland, the legendary home of Elvis Presley?", "answer": "Memphis, Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d8", "question": "By what name is Theodore Kaczynski better known?", "answer": "The Unabomber", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bc1d99ed702eaa27a66982a", "question": "Which Swedish musician sang the song \"Save Tonight\"?", "answer": "Eagle-Eye Cherry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523e38736d4be723796b4c", "question": "Which region of Canada would you find Canada\u2019s Technology Triangle?", "answer": "Waterloo Region", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071ec93745b36be73039e5", "question": "In the \"Revival\" comic book series, what is the family name of the brothers who try to sell parts of the revivers?", "answer": "Check", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7e20ff048f679a45ac07", "question": "Atelophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Imperfection", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c67", "question": "What Stephen King novel features the characters Annie Wilkes and Paul Sheldon?", "answer": "Misery", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a77", "question": "Eric Burdon was the front-man of what two 1960's bands?", "answer": "The Animals and War", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd770e347d002c297e4c3", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Diana?", "answer": "Artemis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac13", "question": "Which ocean surrounds the Union of the Comoros?", "answer": "Indian Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acca", "question": "What city became capital of Cuba in 1519?", "answer": "Havana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5b226ce05a3942286e12", "question": "What kind of animal is \"Knuckles,\" the companion of Sonic the Hedgehog?", "answer": "Knuckles is an echidna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a62b", "question": "What river flows along the southern border of South Carolina?", "answer": "Savannah River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5db", "question": "Which mega city's name translated means \"Eastern Capital\"?", "answer": "Tokyo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e6", "question": "What year was carbon 14 first discovered?", "answer": "1940", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b47501dd7bf43be5e7c0", "question": "What ingredient makes up at least 51% of bourbon mash?", "answer": "Corn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdfbaa8003d27d341092bc4", "question": "What are Easter Island's famous statues called?", "answer": "Moai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff8", "question": "Bibliophobia is a fear or hatred of what?", "answer": "Books", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c3788815febcc896f9271", "question": "How many feet are there in a fathom?", "answer": "Six", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c939fbde8045e48466e9", "question": "Which farm animal has the largest eyes of any land mammal?", "answer": "Horses -- They perceive objects 50% larger than human eyes do. Horses also have monocular vision -- they see things with one eye.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339684", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who shot Mr. Burns?", "answer": "Maggie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b26d", "question": "What ship carried Captain Cook to Australia?", "answer": "Endeavour", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e3", "question": "What plant does the vanilla bean come from?", "answer": "The orchid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb6", "question": "Which country won the first ever FIFA World Cup?", "answer": "Uruguay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab94b786faa38a764be50f", "question": "Who bought the rights to manufacture the Isetta in the 1950\u2019s from the Italian company Iso?", "answer": "BMW", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339204", "question": "What is Miss Piggy's surname?", "answer": "Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c700", "question": "On the periodic table, an element\u2019s atomic number represents the number of what in it's atom?", "answer": "Protons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caae", "question": "What do zoologists call the leader of a wolf pack?", "answer": "The alpha male", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b15", "question": "What is the name of the bar Peter Griffin and his buddies frequent on \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "The Drunken Clam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb7", "question": "Portia Simpson-Miller was the leader of what country?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4bef49076251badbeaca", "question": "Which U.S. President had his sister initially serve as First Lady?", "answer": "Grover Cleveland -- \u00a0His sister Rose Cleveland took on the duties of First Lady until he married his bride Frances in June 1886.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cbc", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional \"The Mystic Knights of the Sea\" fraternity?", "answer": "Amos 'n' Andy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b728", "question": "How many reindeer does Santa have?", "answer": "Nine if you include old Rudy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b35", "question": "In 1976, who was the first woman to become a national network news co-anchor?", "answer": "Barbara Walters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd3", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was Hippomenes also known as?", "answer": "Melanion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef5eca6ce05a3942286e39", "question": "Which Toadies song was part of \"The Cable Guy\" soundtrack released in 1996?", "answer": "Unattractive", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feccd3aec223966ae8f88aa", "question": "What is the name of the event where tributes are chosen for \"The Hunger Games\"?", "answer": "The Reaping", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a54", "question": "What university presents the annual Pulitzer Prize journalism awards?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea8339ff048f679a45ac26", "question": "What is the fastest sense?", "answer": "Hearing", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339462", "question": "Who is Sulley's sidekick in the movie \"Monsters, Inc.\"?", "answer": "Mike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc49a6ce05a3942286f34", "question": "What is the motto of the fictional Addams family?", "answer": "\"Sic gorgiamus allos subjectatos nunc\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ed4", "question": "What horror movie was based on the novel \"Ratman's Notebooks\"?", "answer": "Willard", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133affa", "question": "What general led the Confederates at the Battle of Gettysburg?", "answer": "General Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d1184b4fea7fe947a22283", "question": "What is the correct name for brown coal?", "answer": "Lignite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d7", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Selma's Choice,\" Homer can't go to Duff Gardens because he's sick from eating what?", "answer": "An old, old sandwich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c589", "question": "What is an Anhinga?", "answer": "A bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390cb", "question": "What year did Jean Anouilh write the play \"L'Alouette\"?", "answer": "1952", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9384a6bd93ce3a4e5f682", "question": "Insectophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Insects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6018bc34d96d05b23b281654", "question": "In which country did Buddhism originate?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5990b013b72eedf883a8c70e", "question": "In what country do people speak the language they call Nihongo?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b294", "question": "What president proposed the Great Society?", "answer": "Lyndon Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea4a7dff048f679a45abc4", "question": "What is the summer counterpart of hibernation?", "answer": "Estivation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3c21ff048f679a45ab3c", "question": "Cacophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Ugliness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c12f", "question": "What was boxer Arnold Raymond Cream's nickname?", "answer": "Jersey Joe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5941281cbab1e6f9796f1b5a", "question": "In what sport with animals do you find \"coursing\"?", "answer": "Greyhound racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921b", "question": "What instrument did Sting play with the band \"The Police\"?", "answer": "Bass guitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339355", "question": "What year did \"The Captain Kangaroo Show\" first air?", "answer": "1955", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c5f", "question": "The movie \"American Graffiti\" was released in what year?", "answer": "1973", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3893ff048f679a45ab25", "question": "What color catches the eye first?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a4", "question": "What Michael Keaton film gives mortals a peek into a Handbook for the Recently Deceased?", "answer": "Beetlejuice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe77014eec85e375820b2f4", "question": "Which body of water is the Nile River\u2019s primary reservoir?", "answer": "Lake Victoria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af89", "question": "Who was the second president of the US?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c576877e98cb977789af", "question": "What is the least populous country in Africa?", "answer": "Seychelles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f1", "question": "Who made his directorial debut with the 1966 movie \"Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf\"?", "answer": "Mike Nichols", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca0f", "question": "People with hypertrichosis have lots of what?", "answer": "Hair", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c878", "question": "What's the world's largest predatory fish?", "answer": "The great white shark", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a68b", "question": "Camp Lejeune Marine Corps Base is located in which US state?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339135", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Hamlet\", who is the daughter of Polonius?", "answer": "Ophelia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ad", "question": "What does the \"PJ\" stand for in the name PJ Harvey?", "answer": "Polly Jean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395fc", "question": "Who played Ashley Judd's husband in the 1999 movie \"Double Jeopardy\"?", "answer": "Bruce Greenwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf13", "question": "What colour caps do the Australian cricket team wear?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3c3244f032c0db195b48a", "question": "Who was the first Hawaiian king to venture off the islands?", "answer": "Kamehameha II\u00a0and Queen Kamamalu visited England, where they both contracted measles and died shortly thereafter.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab8c", "question": "Which Gulf is located southwest of Cambodia?", "answer": "Gulf of Thailand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392df", "question": "For what does the \"T\" stand in the name of Star Trek's captain James T. Kirk?", "answer": "Tiberius", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe699fd20565ad31a57c74f", "question": "What 19th-century engineer devised an internal combustion engine which works without a spark plug?", "answer": "Rudolf Diesel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad4c", "question": "Who was the fifth president of the United States?", "answer": "James Monroe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f16a4af7c52aae91cc07da", "question": "Who is Prospero's daughter in Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\"?", "answer": "Miranda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee6", "question": "Who preceded Georges Pompidou as French President?", "answer": "Charles de Gaulle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7d02d877e98cb97778a5c", "question": "The Catedral de Sal, a cathedral carved entirely out of salt, is located in what country?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594a62e32ebb971c1417fb94", "question": "The \"Turbot War\" was a fishing dispute between Canada and what other country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9b99a364247bf200fb88e", "question": "Ostraconophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Shellfish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b0", "question": "What Oscar-winning Best Picture is named for a type of rose?", "answer": "American Beauty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5d", "question": "What literary work inspired Sting's \"Moon Over Bourbon Street\" song?", "answer": "Interview with a Vampire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ebb", "question": "In 1995, who did Drew Barrymore flash on air as a forty-eight birthday present?", "answer": "David Letterman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f75", "question": "What school does Harry Potter attend?", "answer": "Hogwarts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b10", "question": "In the X-Men comics, what element is fused with Wolverine's bones?", "answer": "Adamantium", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf5", "question": "In what movies is the Okinawan sword-maker Hattori Hanzo a character?", "answer": "Kill Bill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af8", "question": "Which character killed Grendel?", "answer": "Beowulf", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a478", "question": "Lanzarote is part of which island group?", "answer": "The Canaries", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d85", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Christopher Wallace?", "answer": "The Notorious B.I.G.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab12", "question": "What is the capital of the Australian state of Tasmania?", "answer": "Hobart", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f7", "question": "What was the name of the first orbiter of NASA's space shuttle program?", "answer": "Enterprise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a075", "question": "Who was the first woman to appear naked on the front cover of \"Radio Times\"?", "answer": "Helen Mirren", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad65", "question": "In 1701, who invented the seed-planting drill?", "answer": "Jethro Tull", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d50", "question": "What oddly worded catchphrase earned Whitney Houston a \"Big Quote\" nomination from VH-1 in 2005?", "answer": "Hell to the no!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae863427f28483af1e7fdc9", "question": "What was the last imperial dynasty of China?", "answer": "Qing Dynasty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971f", "question": "Which Australian played James Bond?", "answer": "George Lazenby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a46", "question": "For what song did R&B singer Seal take home the Grammy Award for both Song and Record of the Year in 1996?", "answer": "Kiss From a Rose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b122", "question": "What was the two-word code name for Woodward and Bernstein's secret Watergate source?", "answer": "Deep Throat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c77cd2f24f0f7a362efd541", "question": "What country is home to the Negev Desert?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a09", "question": "Who played the first \"Tool Time Girl\" on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Pamela Anderson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe64163ae7e414034b5aeac", "question": "What was the name of Al Capone's criminal organization?", "answer": "The Outfit", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59da1ad3f6756c9b30ba14f3", "question": "Which Mediterranean island is said to be named after its inhabitants who were skilled in the use of slings?", "answer": "The Balearic Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133888c", "question": "Who wrote \"A Farewell to Arms\"?", "answer": "Earnest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c550fbde8045e48466ab", "question": "Which ocean mammal is nicknamed the killer whale?", "answer": "Orca -- Orcas are called killer whales due to their aggression while hunting prey.  However, orcas are large dolphins, not whales.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6012150063c99d48cd169ae5", "question": "Einstein won the 1921 Nobel Prize for Physics for explaining what?", "answer": "Photoelectric effect -- However, that did not stop him from giving a lecture\u00a0on relativity in his acceptance speech.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59cdb54b65ff7d326b622a90", "question": "In Shakespeare's play \"Titus Andronicus\", who is Titus' daughter?", "answer": "Lavinia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf5e", "question": "The Sejm are the legislative body in which country?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c435", "question": "What is the only bone in the human body that doesn't connect with any other?", "answer": "Hyoid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a22", "question": "What Beatrix Potter character was rescued by a collie and two foxhounds?", "answer": "Jemima Puddleduck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bc2", "question": "In what year was David Bowie inducted into The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame?", "answer": "1996", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7ebfdb24f84e0b9f9ffe2", "question": "The song \"Honolulu Baby\" was written for which Laurel and Hardy film?", "answer": "Sons of the Desert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f95aeff55722f97b22684d7", "question": "In the \"Star Wars\" franchise, how many languages is C-3PO fluent in?", "answer": "Over six million", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339489", "question": "Who played the warden in the movie \"Natural Born Killers\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae863c07f28483af1e7fdcb", "question": "How many states does India have?", "answer": "29", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339630", "question": "Which TV show's theme song starts with the words \"Come and knock on my door...\"?", "answer": "Three's Company", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5a", "question": "What was the name of the town where all the characters lived in the comic strip \u201cL\u2019il Abner\u201d?", "answer": "Dogpatch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5952489b736d4be723796b74", "question": "What singer, who went to #1 in 1980 with \"Lookin\u2019 For Love\", published \"Still Lookin\u2019 For Love\", as his autobiography?", "answer": "Johnny Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe37ab70ada16518afdc05b", "question": "What did Nazi Germany use Zyklon B for?", "answer": "To kill people in concentration camps", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfe9", "question": "What is the fear of one's own fears known as?", "answer": "Phobophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e3", "question": "Cavatappi pasta, also known as Cellentani, is shaped like what?", "answer": "Corkscrews", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a8", "question": "\"Sphenopalatine Ganglioneuralgia\" is commonly referred to as?", "answer": "Brain freeze", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b323315bf195a31e15d7397", "question": "Blitz, Boondock, Bristol, Scrunge and Squop are terms used in what game?", "answer": "Tiddlywinks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe768b2eec85e375820b2a5", "question": "What does the orange color on Ireland's flag represent?", "answer": "Protestants", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4ed9606d333868d34d76e", "question": "In what type of language does the meaning change based on your pitch?", "answer": "Tonal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bd05d3e40191c55fd523fb6", "question": "Who is the archenemy of Spider-Man?", "answer": "Spider-Man doesn't have a single archenemy but a number of them", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f0b6ff048f679a45aaa4", "question": "Somniphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Sleep", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133907f", "question": "Who wrote a book about John Harrison, entitled \"Longitude\"?", "answer": "Dava Sobel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2f8", "question": "Which character did Raquel Welch play in the 1966 science fiction film \"Fantastic Voyage\"?", "answer": "Cora", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb67", "question": "What is the name of the six-pointed star which is the symbol of Judaism?", "answer": "Star of David", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f96bfa5fdd6dd25324f7", "question": "Who created \"The Scarlet Pimpernel\"?", "answer": "Baroness Orczy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23d", "question": "What was Elton John's fourth studio album?", "answer": "Madman Across the Water", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d9a", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Sawyer?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fe", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman goddess Venus?", "answer": "Aphrodite", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d2", "question": "What did Harry Houdini die from on Halloween in 1926?", "answer": "Ruptured appendix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590682b1ff9c0647b50a809f", "question": "What is the name of the little boy who disappeared in the beginning of the \"Stranger Things\" Netflix series?", "answer": "Will Byers", "category": "entertainment"}]